James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email <u>james-priest@outlook.com</u> • Website <u>https://james-priest.github.io</u>

SUMMARY

Full Stack React, DB, .NET Developer with 20 years experience building large-scale web and mobile applications

SKILLS

Web: HTML5, CSS3, DOM, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI Languages: JavaScript, C#, VB.NET, SQL, RegEx Frameworks: React, Redux, ASP.NET, Node.js, jQuery Data: Stored procs, functions, triggers, Relational/NoSQL

Design: Responsive UI, Accessible & Usable UX **Host:** GitHub Pages, Netlify, Heroku, Azure Web

HTML5 APIs: IDB, Cache API, Fetch API, Promise API **Version Control:** Git, GitHub, SVN, Azure DevOps **Build:** NPM, Grunt, Gulp, Webpack, Parcel, Yeoman **IDEs:** VS Code, Visual Studio, SSMS, MySQL WB

Cloud: Azure DevOps, AWS, RestDB.io **Static Site Gen:** Jekyll, Gatsby, Markdown

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Developer / Technology Director

Velodea

Pasadena, CA

04/2006 - 03/2017

- Successfully built hundreds of website solutions and marketing campaigns for Fortune 500 companies including Shell, Qualcomm, Sprint, Maserati, Fox, Miramax, ABC, J. Walter Thompson, & Edelman.
- Developed dozens of web application systems using ASP.NET, PHP/LAMP, & SQL relational databases.
- Designed large-scale medical management system to track & schedule education of 85,000 students.

Lead Developer & Founder

La Canada, CA

devAware Technology Solutions

07/2002 - 03/2006

- Hired by Sony to build advanced kiosk application for VIAO laptops. Had successful nationwide rollout.
- Engineered web & desktop platform to promote major motion picture releases for Fox & Miramax.

Lead Developer

Milan, Italy, Los Angeles, CA

The Velodea Group / Bleu22 Studios

07/2000 – 07/2002

- Developed real-time web analytics platform to provide behavioral tracking, client usage, & reporting.
- Built a proprietary asset & client management system. Licensed it to Sony, Qualcomm, & Shell Oil.

Release Program Manager

Redmond, WA

Microsoft

11/1998 – 06/2000

- Designed app suite to manage thousands of software releases each month to the corporate website. This mission-critical suite was used to automated the release of product worldwide in under 3 hours.
- Build web-based training system to provide CBT to employees and non-technical business owners.
- Engineered tracking & guery system to manage media shipments of software to third-party vendors.

EDUCATION

DeVry University	Pomona, CA	
B.A. Computer Information Systems	Graduated with Honors – GPA 3.52/4.00	

CERTIFICATIONS

React Nanodegree (React, Redux, React Native), Udacity	6-month term	June 2019
Google Mobile Web Specialist Nanodegree, Udacity	6-month term	October 2018
Grow with Google Scholarship, Mobile Web Development, Udacity	3-month term	April 2018
JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	December 2017
Responsive Web Design, freeCodeCamp	300 hours	July 2017

James R. Priest

5111 Princess Anne Road, La Canada, CA 91011 • Cell 626-240-9970 Email james-priest@outlook.com • Website https://james-priest.github.io

RECENT PROJECTS

Mobile Flashcards App

June 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MTVhSc Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2FhBE06

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2KqJE3i Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2Irc8ay



React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Redux Thunk, Expo, Animations, Notifications



Triathlon Fitness App

React Native, Redux, React Navigation, Geolocation, Notifications, Expo

Would You Rather Game

April 2019

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2MVL2Ng Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2RkLflc



December 2018

May 2019

North

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2x1xwwL Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KYE0EJ



React, Redux, React Router, Redux Thunk, Auth, REST API, RestDB, Semantic-UI-React



PWA, IndexedDB, Cache API, Promise API, Service Worker, REST API, RestDB

CSS Grid Learning App

June 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2WR0Gcz Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2KpZ3AB



JavaScript ES6, CSS3 Animations, RegEx, Advanced DOM Manipulation

Weather Forecast App

March 2018

GitHub: https://bit.ly/2IphkM8
Live Demo: https://bit.ly/2MRbgQP



HTML5, Geolocation API, Semantic UI, CSS3 Animations, Async Web API